For centuries, people have moved to and lived in cities.
几个世纪以来，人们不断迁移并居住在城市里。
These sprawling urban centres are places to find work, friends and fun.
这些不断扩展的城市中心是人们寻找工作、结交朋友和享受乐趣的地方。
It's no surprise that they continue to grow as more and more people flood in hoping to make the most of the opportunities they offer but adding to the congestion and pollution that already exists.
毫不奇怪，随着越来越多的人涌入城市，希望充分利用城市提供的各种机会，城市还在持续发展壮大，但这也加剧了已经存在的拥堵和污染问题。
According to a report by the United Nations, 54 per cent of the world's population lives in urban areas and it predicts that by 2050, this figure will have increased to around 70 per cent.
根据联合国的一份报告，全球54%的人口居住在城市地区，并且该报告预测，到2050年，这一比例将上升到大约70%。
But as more and more people migrate from the countryside to the city to get better opportunities, they can end up with nowhere to live.
但是，随着越来越多的人从农村迁移到城市以获取更好的机会，他们最终将没有地方来生存。
This is true in places such as Rio de Janeiro, where migrants can't rent or buy a home, and they end up building their own communities and houses on unoccupied land.
在诸如里约热内卢这样的地方就是如此，移民们租不起也买不起房子，于是他们最终在闲置的土地上建造起自己的社区和房屋。
These are called shanty towns - poor communities where the houses are built out of cheap materials like corrugated iron and plastic sheeting — and often don't have any electricity or water supply.
这些地方被称为棚户区——贫困社区，那里的房屋是用波纹铁皮和塑料布等廉价材料建造的——而且通常没有电和水供应。
These are, of course, not the megacities of the future we want to see.
当然，这些并不是我们希望看到的未来的特大城市的样子。
Some serious urban planning is needed to make our cities of the future good, safe and modern places to live in.
需要进行一些严肃的城市规划，以使我们未来的城市成为良好、安全且现代化的宜居之地。
This involves improving the infrastructure, the housing conditions and also the opportunities for education and employment.
这包括改善基础设施、住房条件，以及增加教育和就业机会。
Something urban planners are looking at now is the creation of 'smart cities'.
城市规划者们目前正在关注的一件事是“智慧城市”的创建。
According to John Rossant, founder and chairman of the non-profit organisation New Cities Foundation, technology is the way forward.
据非营利组织新城市基金会的创始人兼主席约翰·罗桑特称，科技是未来的发展方向。
He thinks that it's generally accepted that "cloud computing, ubiquitous internet, robust 5G networks etc, will transform our cities."
他认为，“云计算、无处不在的互联网、强大的5G网络等等，将改变我们的城市”这一观点已被普遍接受。
He says technology is really "a game changer", in urbanisation.
他说，在城市化进程中，科技确实是“改变游戏规则的因素”。
It would collect large amounts of data about how a city is performing and may improve how a city functions.
它将收集大量有关城市运行情况的数据，并有可能改善城市运行的方式。
This may sound like a utopian view.
这听起来可能像是一种乌托邦式的观点。
For now, some cities and conurbations around the world are trying out more low-tech schemes to try and make them desirable places to live and work in.
目前，世界上一些城市和城市群正在尝试更多的低技术方案，试图使它们成为理想的生活和工作场所。
Building shared-ownership housing and improving public transport are some ways.
建设共有产权住房和改善公共交通就是一些方法。
And encouraging cycling and building bike lanes can keep the population healthy and cut down on smog.
而且鼓励骑自行车和修建自行车道可以让人们保持健康，同时减少雾霾。
What would make your city a better place to live in?
你认为怎么做能让你的城市成为一个更宜居的地方呢？